Rebel. Genius. Liberator.
Luther is a drama, history film directed by Eric Till.
During the early 16th century, idealistic German monk Martin Luther, disgusted by the materialism
in the church, begins the dialogue that will lead to the Protestant Reformation.
Martin Luther, played by Joseph Fiennes.
Girolamo Aleander, played by Jonathan Firth.
Katharina von Bora, played by Claire Cox.
Johann Tetzel, played by Alfred Molina.
Frederick, played by Peter Ustinov.
Johann von Staupitz, played by Bruno Ganz.
Luther is a 2003 historical drama film dramatizing the life of
Protestant Christian reformer Martin Luther.
It is directed by Eric Till and stars Joseph Fiennes in the title role.
Alfred Molina, Jonathan Firth, Claire Cox, Bruno
Ganz, and Sir Peter Ustinov co-star.
The film covers Luther's life from his becoming a friar in 1505,
to his trial before the Diet of Augsburg in 1530.
The American-German co-production was partially funded by Thrivent
Financial for Lutherans, a Christian financial services company.
The film explores themes of affectation, protestant
church, church, catholicism, historical drama.
The tone is emotional.